American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf. 1866-1886 APS.Archives.IIf APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 13, 1885; 9x6; Lea Brothers & Company
    Phila., L. 1p. Unable to furnish publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 13, 1885; 9x6; Philadelphia College of Pharmacy
    Phila., A.L.S.:Tho[mas] S.Wiegand,librarian. 1p. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 13, 1885; 8x5; American Philological Association
    Hanover, N.H., A.L.S.:John H[enry] Wright,secretary. 3p.,end. Cannot exchange publications. Refers to J.P.Lesley.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 14, 1885; 10x7-1/2; Rhode Island Historical Society
    Providence, A.L.S.:Amos Perry,librarian. 1p. Exchange of publications. Refers to article by W.Staples.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 14, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; University of Michigan
    Ann Arbor, A.L.S.:R[aymond] C[azallis] Davis,librarian 1p.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 14, 1885; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:N.P.Scudder. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 14, 1885; 3x5; Essex Institute
    Salem, L.on postal card S.:W[illia]m P.Upham, librarian, 1p.,end.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to H[enr]y Phillips, Feb. 14, 1885; 3x5; Hotchkiss, Jedediah, 1828-1899
    Staunton, Va., L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Asking for advance copy of J.Stevenson's article. Refers to J.P.Lesley.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 15, 1885; 9-1/2x6; Appleton, A. J.
    Winchester, Mass., L. 1p., end. Asking list of Society's publications for new edition of the American catalogue.
  - Letter to Prof. Jos. P. Lesley(sic), Feb. 16, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Agnew, D. Hayes (David Hayes), 1818-1892
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.,end. Suggests his obituary of E.R.Beadle be put in pamphlet form.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 16, [1885]; 5x3; New Haven Colony Historical Society
    New Haven, Conn., A.L.on postal card S.:Thomas R.Trowbridge, secretary. 1p.,end.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Memorandum pertaining to publications of the Society sent to Johns Hopkins university, February 16, 1885; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
  - Letter to Jed[ediah] Hotchkiss, Staunton, Va., Feb. 17, 1885; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    A.Dr.of L.S.:H[enry] P[hillips],secretary. 1p.,end.by D[aniel] G.Brinton. His request is granted.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 21, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Heliotype Printing Co.
    Boston, L. 1p.and end. Concerning printing matter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 21, 1885; 10x8; University of Michigan
    Ann Arbor, Mich., A.L.S.:R[aymond] C[azallis] Davis,librarian. 2p.,end. Publications. Mentions [P.S.] DuPonceau,[A.D.] Bache,G.B.Wood.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 22, 1885; 8x5; Stevens, W. LeConte (Walter LeConte), 1847-1927
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 4p.,end. Ballooning experiments. Mentions D. Rittenhouse,Hopkins,G.Barker.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 24, 1885; 8-1/2x5; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, L.S.:N.Murray. 1p.,end. Thanks for publications. Mentions D.C.Gilman.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Feb. 24, 1885; 9-1/2x8; United States. Patent Office
    Wash.,D.c., T.L.S.:Schuyler Duryee,chief clerk. 1p., end. Requesting publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 24, 1885; 8x5; Stevens, W. LeConte (Walter LeConte), 1847-1927
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 3p.,end. Ballooning experiments. Refers to J. Charles, D.Rittenhouse, Pilâtre de Rozier, B.Franklin. FILM54-66 FRAME 166
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 26, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Buffalo Public Library (Buffalo, N.Y.)
    Buffalo, A.L.S.:J[osephus] N[elson] Larned. 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Feb. 28, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Chicago Historical Society
    Chicago, A.L.S.:Albert D[avid] Hager,secretary. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 28, 1885; 8x5; Cornell University
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S.:G[eorge] W[illia]m Harris,librarian 1p.,end. Asking for publication. Refers to T.F. Crane.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 2, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Buffalo Public Library (Buffalo, N.Y.)
    Buffalo, A.L.S.:J[osephus] N[elson] Larned. 2p. Exchange of publications. Financial resources of his library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 4, 1885; 8x5; Yale University
    New Haven, A.L.S.:A[ddison] Van Name. 1p.and end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 5, 1885; 8x5; Hay, Oliver Perry, 1846-1930
    Irvington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Asking price of publications.
  - Bill for the American philosophical society, March 6, 1885; 8-1/2x5; Heliotype Printing Co.
    D. 1p.,end.by [Henry] Phillips.
  - Letter to O[liver] P[erry] Hay, Irvington, Ind., March 9, 1885; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Phila.], A.Dr.of L.S.:H[enry] P[hillips]. 1p. Mutilated. Price of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 9, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Buffalo Public Library (Buffalo, N.Y.)
    Buffalo, A.L.S. :J[osephus] N[elson] Larned. 2p., end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 11, 1885; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Society business. Financial matters.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 12, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    A.L.S. 1p. Asking for favor. Mentions the Smith-sonian institution.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 12, 1885; 8x5; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Phila., A.L.S.:F[rederick] D[awson] Stone,librarian. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends money.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 13, 1885; 8x5; Button, Conyers
    Germantown, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Requesting privilege of making a copy of the portrait of J.Priestley.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, [March] 13, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.and end. Asking authorization for use of his plate in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 16, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Hale, Horatio, 1817-1896
    Clinton, [Canada], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 17, 1885; 5x3; W. B. Clarke & Carruth
    Boston, L.on postal card. 1p.,end.and add. Order for publication. Attached to same sheet is letter from W.B.Clarke & Carruth to H.Phillips, March 28, 1885.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 17, 1885; 8x5; Taylor, W. Curtis
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Refers to his photograph of the officers of the American association for the advancement of science.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 18, 1885; 8x5; Harvard University
    Cambridge, A.L.S.:W[illia]m H[opkins] Tillinghast. 1p.,end. Seeking information for use in his school's catalogue.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 18, 1885; 10-1/2x8; Philadelphia. Post office
    Phila., T.L.S.:H[enry] S[hippen] Huidekoper,postmaster. 1p. Business.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 18, 1885; 3x5; Taylor, W. Curtis
    Phila., A.L.on postal cards.with initials. 1p. and add. Asking for date when he may meet the members of the Society.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 19, 1885; 8x5; McCauley, Edward Yorke, 1827-1894
    League Island, Pa., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking loan of his manuscript on Egyptology.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 19, 1885; 10x8; University of California, Berkeley
    Berkeley, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:J.H.C.Bonte, J.C.Rowell. 2p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 20, 1885; 8x5; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S.:W[illia]m H[opkins] Tillinghast. 1p.,end. Seeking information for his school's catalogue.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 20, 1885; 9x6; M’Calla & Stavely
    Phila., L. 2p.,end. Offers reasons for the mismatching of the paper that goes into the Proceedings.
  - Letter to H[enr]y Phillips, March 21, 1885; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Macmillan & Co.
    London, Lp.,end.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 24, 1885; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.and end. Obituary notices: W. Sellers for G.Whitney, F.Graff for T.R.Peale.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 24, 1885; 8x5; Graff, Frederick, 1817-1890
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.and end. Obituary notices: W.Sellers for G.Whitney, F.Graff for T.R.Peale.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 24, 1885; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Literary and Philosophical Society of Liverpool
    Liverpool, [Eng.], A.L.S.:Richmond Leigh, librarian. 1p. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 24, 1885; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Refers to new members who have paid their fees, and other Society business. Metioned are J.B.McMaster and W.Cattell, among others.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, March 25, 1885; 8x5; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for kind words about J.L.LeConte. Refers to APS committee on the Hessian fly. Mentions T.Jefferson and M.Carey. On same sheet is note from J.P.L[esley] to [Henry] Phillips, [March, 1885?].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 26, 1885; 8x5-1/2; University of Michigan
    Ann Arbor, A.L.S.:James B[urrill] Angell,president. 2p. Thanks for publications. FILM 199 FRAME 708
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 28, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; W. B. Clarke & Carruth
    Boston, L. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends money for publication. Attached to same sheet as letter from W.B.Clarke & Carruth to APS, March 17, 1885.
  - Letter to H[enr]y Phillips, March 28, 1885; 8x5; Brooklyn Entomological Society
    Brooklyn, A.L.S.: John B[ernhard] Smith,secretary. 1p.and end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 28, 1885; 8x5; Providence Franklin Society
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S.:W.O.Brown. 3p.,end.and enc. Exchange of publications. Enclosure is a newspaper clipping about lectures given before his society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 28, 1885; 10-1/2x8; Rhode Island Society for the Encouragement of Domestic Industry
    Providence, A.L.S.:C.W.Smith,secretary. 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 30, 1885; 10-1/2x8; New York State Library
    Albany, A.L.S.:H[enry] A[ugustus] Homes. 2p., end. Concerning publications. Refers to D.Murray.
  - Note to [Henry] Phillips, March, 1885?; 8x5; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    []. A.N.in 3rd.P.S.with initials. 1p. Requests search for record of APS committee on the Hessian fly. On same sheet as letter from H.A.Hagen to J.P.Lesley, March 25, 1885.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], March, 1885; 8x5; Taylor, W. Curtis
    [Phila., ?] A.L.S. 1P. Requesting privilege to copy portrait of J.Priestley for C.Button.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 2, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Cincinnati Society of Natural History
    Cincinnati, A.L.S.:Jos[eph] F[rancis] James, custodian. 2p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 2, 1885; 8x5; Brooklyn Entomological Society
    Brooklyn, A.L.S.:John B[ernhard] Smith. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 2, 1885; 10x8; Fletcher, E. L.
    Fort Staunton, N.M., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking price of article by E.D.Cope.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Leslie, April 3, 1885; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S.:W[illia]m B[ower] Taylor. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication, compiled by H. Phillips. Concerning J.Henry.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 3, 1885; 10x8; State Historical Society of Wisconsin
    Madison, A.L.S.:D[aniel] S[teele] Durrie,librarian. 1p.,end.and enc. Exchange of publications. Enclosure is a list of publications wanted.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 7, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Naturforschende Gesellschaft in Emden
    Emden, A.L.S.:G.Voss. 1p.,end. In German. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 7, 1885; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:Spencer F[ullerton] Baird, secretary. 1p.,end. Order for APS Minutes. Concerning J. Henry.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 7, 1885; 9-1/2x6; Vassar brothers institute, Poughkeepsie, N.Y.
    Poughkeepsie, N.Y., A.L.S.:W.G.Stevenson. 2p.,end. Concerning publications of his society.
  - Letter to H[enr]y Phillips, April 8, 1885; 8x5; Brooklyn Entomological Society
    Brooklyn, A.L.S.:John B[ernhard] Smith. 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 8, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning the Hessian fly. Refers to Dr.Bond.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 8, 1885; 9x5-1/2; State University of New York at Albany
    Albany, A.L.S.:David Murray. 1p. Concerning publications. Refers to H. Homes.
  - Letter to secretaries of the American philosophical society, April 8, 1885; 9x5-1/2; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 1p.and end....Enc.wanting.... Order for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 9, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Cincinnati Society of Natural History
    Cincinnati, A.L.S.:Jos[eph] F[rancis] James,custodian. 1p.and enc. Exchange of publications. Enclosure is a visiting card.
  - Letter to C.A.Blake [Henry Phillips], secretary of the American philosophical society, April 10, 1885; 11x8-1/2; Hess, J., co.
    New York, A.L.S.:Julius Shen. 1p.,end. Looking for business.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 10, 1885; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S.:W[illia]m B[ower] Taylor. 2p.,end. Thanks for APS Minutes.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 11, 1885; 7-1/2x4; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for proof-sheet.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 11, 1885; 5x3; State Historical Society of Wisconsin
    Madison, A.L.on postal card S.:D[aniel] S[teele] Durrie, librarian. 1p.and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 12, 1885; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Kaiserlich-Königliche Zoologisch-Botanische Gesellschaft in Wien
    Vienna, A.L.on postal card S.:F.Bartich, librarian. 1p.and add. In English. Publications listed are out of print.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 13, 1885; 8x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Recommends using Prof.E.Cope's cut in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 13, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Engineers Club of Philadelphia
    Phila., L.S.:Howard Murphy, secretary. 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Philipps, April 13, 1885; 11x8-1/2; Hess, J., co.
    New York, A.L.S.:Julius Shen. 1p. Concerning his catalogue. Sorry for mistake in name.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 13, 1885; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:S[pencer] F[ullerton] Baird. 1p.... Enc.wanting.... Returns proof-sheet of APS Minutes.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 14, 1885; 5x3; Chase, Pliny Earle, 1820-1886
    Haverford college, Pa., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning title of paper on physics.
  - Letter to [Daniel G. Brinton], April 15, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p.,end.by D.G. Brinton,and end. Enc. Asking approval for enclosed letter to [P.] Chase. For enclosure, see letter from APS to Chase, April 16, 1885.
  - Letter to Prof. P[liny] E.Chase, Haverford college, April 16, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.L.S.:H[enry] Phillips. 1p.and end. Copy. Concerning his paper, which cannot be read unless actually presented. Enclosed originally in letter from Phillips to [D.G.Brinton], April 15, 1885.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 16, 1885; 10x8; Fletcher, E. L.
    Fort Staunton, N.M., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for article by E.D.Cope.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 17, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Cincinnati Society of Natural History
    Cincinnati, A.L.S.: Jos[eph] F[ranis] James, custodian 1p.,end. Thanks for exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, April 17, 1885; 7x4-1/2; DaCosta, Jacob Mandes, 1833-1900
    [Phila], A.L.S. 2p. Declines to prepare obituary of E. Wallace.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 19, 1885; 5-1/2x4-1/2; Sellers, William, 1824-1905
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Accepts appointment to prepare obituary of G.Whitney.
  - Letter to [Pliny Earle] Chase, April 20, 1885; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.Dr.of L.S.:[Henry] Phillips,secretary. 2p.and end. Requests him to follow proper procedure in submitting papers for Society's publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning plate for his paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 21, 1885; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1P...Enc.wanting... Concerning obituaries. Refers to T. Parvin and E. Wallace.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 21, 1885; 8-1/2x5; M’Calla & Stavely
    Phila., L. 2p.,end. Mutilated. Cost of plates for F.Genth's paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 22, 1885; 8-1/2x5; Albany Institute
    Albany, N.Y., A.L.S.:Geo[rge] R[ogers] Howell,librarian. 1p.,end. Sending his institute's publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 22, 1885; 10x8; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
    London, L.S. 5p.and end. Offers reasons why he cannot accept membership in Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 24, 1885; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila], A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 24, 1885; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 25, 1885; 8x5; Stevens, W. LeConte (Walter LeConte), 1847-1927
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Ballooning experiments. Mentions D. Rittenhouse,F.Hopkinson,J.Charles. Also, asks for picture of R.Hare.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 26, 1885; 5x3; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, April 27, 1885; 11x8-1/2; Brockway, C. B.
    Bloomsburg, Pa., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning his paper. On same sheet as letter from J.P.Lesley to C.B.Brockway, Sept. 13, 1884.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 29, 1885; 9-1/2x6; Beadle, Weber H.
    Bridgeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Asking for copies of D.Agnew's obituary of his father, E.R.Beadle.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 29, 1885; 3x5; Dartmouth College
    Hanover, N.H., A.L.on postal card S.:Louis Pollens. 1p. and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 29, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Rawson, Rawson William, Sir, 1812-1899
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], April 30, 1885; 8x5; Winsor, Henry, -1889
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning cost of publishing work by D.Zeisberger. Mentions F.Fraley.
  - Letter to C.B. Brockway, Bloomsburg, Pa., May 1, 1885; 8x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.L.S.:Henry Phillips,secretary. 1p., end.by C.B.Brockway, and end. Concerning reprints of his article.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], May 1, 1885; 8x6; Hotchkiss, Jedediah, 1828-1899
    Staunton, Va., A.L.S. 1p. Asking loan of illustrations. Refers to J.J.Stevenson.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 1, 1885; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    [Edinburgh], L.on postal card S.:P[eter] G[uthrie] Tait 1p.and add. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 2, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Naturforschende gesellschaft zu Freiburg i. B.
    Baden, [Ger.], Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:A.Gruber. 1p.,end. In German. Order for publication.
  - Letter to D[aniel Garrison] Brinton, May 2, 1885; 8x5-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Seeking advice regarding illustrations. On same sheet is note from D.G.Brinton to [Henry Phillips, May 3, 1885?].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 2, 1885; 10x8; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:James C[onstantine] Pilling, chief clerk. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Note to [Henry Phillips;], May 3, 1885?; 8x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.N.S. 1p. Agrees with him regarding illustrations. On same sheet as letter from [Henry] Phillips to D.Brinton, May 2, 1885.
  - Letter to J[edediah] Hotchkiss, Staunton, Va., May 4, 1885; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Dr.of L.S.:Henry Phillips, secretary. 1p.and end. Concerning his request for illustrations.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 5, 1885; 8x5; Stevens, W. LeConte (Walter LeConte), 1847-1927
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for note. Refers to W.Youmans sand J.Hare.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 6, 1885; 8-1/2x6; E. Steiger & Co.
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Order for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 8, 1885; 10x8; United States. Army. Signal Corps
    Wash.,D.C., T.L.S.:W[illiam] B[abcock] Hazen. 1p., end. Asking use of Society's library for collecting material on meteorology.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 9, 1885; 8x5; Royal Philosophical Society of Glasgow
    Glasgow, A.L.S.:John Robertson. 2p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to H[enr]y Phillips, May 11, 1885; 5x3; Hotchkiss, Jedediah, 1828-1899
    Staunton, Va., L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Map and plate almost ready.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 11, 1885; 8-1/2x6; Maine Historical Society
    Portland, A.L.S.:S.J.Bryant,librarian. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 11, 1885; 8x5; Thomas, Allen C. (Allen Clapp), 1846-1920
    Haverford college, Pa., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning his certificate of membership.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 12, 1885; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology
    Wash.,D.C., T.L.S.:James C.Pilling. 1p.,end. Asking for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 14, 1885; 11x8-1/2; California Academy of Sciences
    San Francisco, A.L.S.:M.K.Curran. 2p.,end. Concerning exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 15, 1885; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.and add. Asking change of title on his manuscript.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 15, 1885; 10x8; Minnesota Academy of Natural Sciences
    Minneapolis, L.S.:W.H.Leonard, secretary. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 15, 1885; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Pumpelly, Raphael, 1837-1923
    Newport, R.I., A.L.S. 1p.,and. Asking for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 15, 1885; 8-1/2x11; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, L. 2p. Offer of publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 18, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Cambridge, [Eng.], A.L.S.:J[ohn] P[ercival] Postgate. 2p. and end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 19, 1885; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. says he is getting estimates for an illustration.
  - Letter to Prof. [J.P.] Lesley, May 19, 1885; 6x5; Gill, Theodore, 1837-1914
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning illustrations. Refers to E.Cope.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 19, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Virginia Historical Society
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S.: R[obert] A[lonzo] Brock 3p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 22, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Verein für geographie und statistik, Frankfurt am Main
    Frankfurt, A.L.S.:Dr.Ebrard. 1p.and end. In German Concerning publications. Refers to [Henry] C.Lea.